In the last video, we talked
在之前的课程中 我们谈到
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
about precision and recall as
查准率和召回率
an evaluation metric for classification
作为遇到偏斜类问题
problems with skew classes.
的评估度量值
For many applications, we'll want
在很多应用中
to somehow control the trade
我们希望能够保证
off between position and recall.
查准率和召回率的相对平衡
Let me tell you how
在这节课中
to do that and also show
我将告诉你应该怎么做
you some, even more effective
同时也向你展示一些
ways to use precision and
查准率和召回率
recall as an evaluation
作为算法评估度量值的
metric for learning algorithms.
更有效的方式
As a reminder, here are the
回忆一下
definitions of precision and
这是查准率和召回率的定义
recall from the previous video.
我们在上一节中讲到的
Let's continue our cancer classification
让我们继续用
example, where y equals
癌症分类的例子
one if the patient has cancer
如果病人患癌症 则y=1
and y equals zero otherwise.
反之则y=0
And let's say we've trained in
假设我们用
logistic regression classifier, which outputs
逻辑回归模型训练了数据
probabilities between zero and one.
输出概率在0-1之间的值
So, as usual, we're
因此
going to predict one, y equals
我们预测y=1
one if h of x
如果h(x)
is greater than or equal to
大于或等于0.5
0.5 and predict zero if
预测值为0
the hypothesis outputs a value
如果方程输出值
less than 0.5 and this
小于0.5
classifier may give us
这个回归模型
some value for precision and some value for recall.
能够计算查准率和召回率
But now, suppose we want
但是现在
to predict that a patient
假如我们希望
has cancer only if we're
在我们非常确信地情况下
very confident that they really do.
才预测一个病人得了癌症
Because you know if you go
因为你知道
to a patient and you tell
如果你告诉一个病人
them that they have cancer, it's
告诉他们你得了癌症
going to give them a huge
他们会非常震惊
shock because this is seriously
因为这是一个
bad news and they may
非常坏的消息
end up going through a pretty
而且他们会经历一段
painful treatment process and so on.
非常痛苦的治疗过程
And so maybe we want to
因此我们希望
tell someone that we think
只有在我们非常确信的情况下
they have cancer only if they're very confident.
才告诉这个人他得了癌症
One way to do this would
这样做的一种方法
be to modify the algorithm, so
是修改算法
that instead of setting the
我们不再将临界值
threshold at 0.5, we
设为0.5
might instead say that we'll
也许 我们只在
predict that y is equal
h(x)的值大于或等于0.7
to 1, only if H of
的情况下
x is greater than or equal to 0.7.
才预测y=1
So this, I think
因此
will tell someone if they
我们会告诉一个人
have cancer only if we think
他得了癌症
there's a greater than, greater
在我们认为
than or equal to 70% that they have cancer.
他有大于等于70%得癌症的概率情况下
And if you do this then
如果你这么做
you're predicting some of this
那么你只在
cancer only when you're
非常确信地情况下
more confident, and so
才预测癌症
you end up with a classifier
那么你的回归模型
that has higher precision, because
会有较高的查准率
all the patients that you're
因为所有你准备
going to and say, you know,
告诉他们
we think you have cancer, all
患有癌症的病人
of those patients are now
所有这些人
pretty, once they hear, pretty
有比较高的可能性
confident they actually have cancer.
他们真的患有癌症
And so, a higher fraction of
你预测患有癌症的病人中
the patients that you predict to
有较大比率的人
have cancer, will actually turn
他们确实患有癌症
out to have cancer, because in
因为这是我们
making those predictions we are pretty confident.
在非常确信的情况下做出的预测
But in contrast, this classifier will
与之相反
have lower recall, because
这个回归模型会有较低的召回率
now we are going
因为
to make predictions, we are
当我们做预测的时候
going to predict y equals one, on a smaller number of patients.
我们只给很小一部分的病人预测y=1
Now we could even take this further.
现在我们把这个情况夸大一下
Instead of setting the threshold
我们不再把临界值
at 0.7, we can set
设在0.7
this at 0.9 and we'll predict
我们把它设为0.9
y1 only if we are
我们只在至少90%肯定
more than 90% certain that
这个病人患有癌症的情况下
the patient has cancer, and so,
预测y=1
you know, a large fraction that
那么这些病人当中
those patients will turn out
有非常大的比率
to have cancer and so,
真正患有癌症
this is the high precision classifier
因此这是一个高查准率的模型
will have lower recall because we
但是召回率会变低
want to correctly detect that those patients have cancer.
因为我们希望能够正确检测患有癌症的病人
Now consider a different example.
现在考虑一个不同的例子
Suppose we want to avoid
假设我们希望
missing too many actual cases of cancer.
避免遗漏掉患有癌症的人
So we want to avoid the false negatives.
即我们希望避免假阴性
In particular, if a patient
具体地说
actually has cancer, but we
如果一个病人实际患有癌症
fail to tell them that
但是我们并没有告诉他患有癌症
they have cancer, then that can be really bad.
那这可能造成严重后果
Because if we tell
因为
a patient that they don't
如果我们告诉病人他们没有患癌症
have cancer then they are
那么
not going to go for treatment and
他们就不会接受治疗
if it turns out that they
但是如果
have cancer or we fail
他们患有癌症
to tell them they have
我们又没有告诉他们
cancer, well they may not get treated at all.
那么他们就根本不会接受治疗
And so that would be
那么
a really bad outcome because he
这么可能造成严重后果
died because we told them
病人丧失生命
they don't have cancer they failed
因为我们没有告诉他患有癌症
to get treated, but it turns
他没有接受治疗
out that they actually have cancer.
但事实上他又患有癌症
When in doubt, we want to
这种i情况下
predict that y equals one.
我们希望预测y=1
So when in doubt, we want
我们希望
to predict that they have
预测病人患有癌症
cancer so that at least
这样
they look further into it
他们会做进一步的检测
and this can get treated,
然后接受治疗
in case they do turn out to have cancer.
以避免他们真的患有癌症
In this case, rather than setting
在这个例子中
higher probability threshold, we might
我们不再设置高的临界值
instead take this value
我们会设置另一个值
and this then sets it to
将临界值
a lower value, so maybe
设得较低
0.3 like so.
比如0.3
By doing so, we're saying
这样做
that, you know what, if we
我们认为
think there's more than a 30%
他们有大于30%的几率
chance that they have caner, we better
患有癌症
be more conservative and tell
我们以更加保守的方式
them that they may have cancer,
告诉他们患有癌症
so they can seek treatment if necessary.
因此他们能够接受治疗
And in this case, what
在这种情况下
we would have is going to
我们会有一个
be a higher recall classifier,
较高召回率的模型
because we're going to
因为
be correctly flagging a higher
确实患有癌症的病人
fraction of all of
有很大一部分
the patients that actually do have
被我们正确标记出来了
cancer, but we're going
但是
to end up with lower precision,
我们会得到较低的查准率
because the higher fraction of
因为
the patients that we said have
我们预测患有癌症的病人比例越大
cancer, the higher fraction of them will turn out not to have cancer after all.
那么就有较大比例的人其实没有患癌症
And by the way, just as an
顺带一提
aside, when I talk
当我在给
about this to other
别的学生讲这个的时候
students up until before, it's pretty amazing.
令人惊讶的是
Some of my students say is
有的学生问
how I can tell the story both ways.
怎么可以从两面来看这个问题
Why we might want to have
为什么我总是
higher precision or higher recall
只想要高查准率或高召回率
and the story actually seems to work both ways.
但是这看起来可以使两边都提高
But I hope the details of
但是我希望
the algorithm is true and the
算法是正确的
more general principle is, depending
更普遍的一个原则是
on where you want, whether
这取决于你想要什么
you want high precision, lower recall
你想要高查准率 低召回率
or higher recall, lower precision, you
还是高召回率 低查准率
can end up predicting y equals
你可以预测y=1
one when h(x) is greater than some threshold.
当h(x)大于某个临界值
And so, in general, for
因此 总的来说
most classifiers, there is going
对于大多数的回归模型
to be a trade off between precision and recall.
你得权衡查准率和召回率
And as you vary the value
当你改变
of this threshold, this value,
临界值的值时
this special that I have
我在这儿画了一个
joined here, you can actually
临界值
plot us some curve that
你可以画出曲线
trades off precision and
来权衡查准率
recall, where a value
和召回率
up here, this would correspond
这里的一个值
to a very high value of
反应出一个较高的临界值
the threshold, maybe threshold equals
这个临界值可能等于0.99
over 0.99, so that say, predict
我们假设
y equals 1 only where
只在有大于99%的确信度的情况下
no more than 99 percent
才预测y=1
confident, at least 99
至少
percent probability this once, so
有99%的可能性
that will be a precision relatively
因此这个点反应高查准率
low recall, whereas the point
低召回率
down here will correspond to
然而这里的一个点
a value of the threshold that's
反映一个较低的临界值
much lower, maybe 0.01.
比如说0.01
When in doubt at all, put down y1.
毫无疑问 在这里预测y=1
And if you do that, you
如果你这么做
end up with a much
你最后会得到
lower precision higher recall classifier.
很低的查准率 但是较高的召回率
And as you vary the threshold, if
当你改变临界值
you want, you can actually trace
如果你愿意
all the curve from your classifier
你可以画出回归模型的所有曲线
to see the range of different values you can get for precision recall.
来看看你能得到的查准率和召回率的范围
And by the way, the position
顺带一提
recall curve can look like many different shapes.
查准率-召回率曲线可以是各种不同的形状
Sometimes it'll look this, sometimes
有时它看起来是这样
it'll look like that.
有时是那样
Now, there are many different possible
查准率-召回率曲线的形状
shapes in the position of recall
有很多可能性
curve, depending on the details of the classifier.
这取决于回归模型的具体算法
So this raises another
因此这又产生了
interesting question which is, is
另一个有趣的问题
there a way to choose
那就是
this threshold automatically?
有没有办法自动选取临界值
Or, more generally, if we have
或者 更广泛地说
a few different algorithms or a
如果我们有不同的算法
few different ideas for algorithms, how
或者不同的想法
do we compare different precision recall numbers?
我们如何比较不同的查准率和召回率呢？
completely.
具体来说
Suppose we have three different
假设我们有三个
learning algorithms, or actually maybe
不同的学习算法
these are three different learning algorithms, may
或者这三个不同的学习曲线
be these are the same algorithm, but just with different values for the threshold.
是同样的算法 但是临界值不同
How do we decide which of these algorithms is best?
我们怎样决定哪一个算法是最好的
One of the things we talked
我们之前讲到的
about earlier is the importance
其中一件事就是
of a single real number evaluation metric.
评估度量值的重要性
And that is the idea of
这个概念是
having a number that just
通过一个具体的数字
tells you how well is your classifier doing.
来反映你的回归模型到底如何
But by switching to the precision
但是查准率和召回率的问题
recall metric, we've actually lost that.
我们却不能这样做
We now have two real numbers.
因为在这里我们有两个可以判断的数字
And so we often end up
因此 我们经常会
facing situations, like if
不得不面对这样的情况
we are trying to compare algorithm 1
如果我们正在试图比较算法1
to algorithm 2, we
和算法2
end up asking ourselves, Is a
我们最后问自己
position of point five and
到底是0.5的查准率与
a recall of point four, well
0.4的召回率好
is that better or worse than
还是说
a position of point seven or
0.7的查准率与
a recall point one?
0.1的召回率好
If every time you try
或者每一次
on a new algorithm you end up
你设计一个新算法
having to sit around and think
你都要坐下来思考
well, maybe point five
到底0.5 0.4好
point four, is better than point
还是说
seven point one, maybe not, I do not know.
0.7 0.1好 我不知道
If you end up having to sit around and think and make these decisions.
如果你最后这样坐下来思考
that really slows down your
这回降低
decision making process, for what
你的决策速度
changes are useful to incorporate into your algorithm.
思考到底哪些改变是有用的 应该被融入到你的算法
Where as in contrast, if we
与此相反的是
had a single real number evaluation metric,
如果我们有一个评估度量值
like a number that just
一个数字
tells us is either algorithm 1 or is algorithm 2 better.
能够告诉我们到底是算法1好还是算法2好
That helps us much more
这能够帮助我们
quickly decide which algorithm to
更快地决定
go with and helps us
哪一个算法更好
as well to much more quickly
同时也能够更快地帮助我们
evaluate different changes that we
评估不同的改动
may be contemplating for an algorithm.
哪些应该被融入进算法里面
So, how can we get
那么 我们怎样才能
a single real number evaluation metric.
得到这个评估度量值呢？
One natural thing that you
你可能会去尝试的
might try is to look
一件事情是
at the average between precision and recall.
计算一下查准率和召回率的平均值
So using p and r
用 P 和 R
to denote position and recall, what
来表示查准率和召回率
you could do is just compute the
你可以做的是
average and look at what classifier
计算它们的平均值
has the highest average value.
看一看哪个模型有最高的均值
But this turns out not to
但是这可能
be such a good solution because, similar
并不是一个很好的解决办法
to the example we had earlier,
因为 像我们之前的例子一样
it turns out that if we
如果我们的回归模型
have a classifier that predicts
总是预测
y1 all the time, then if
y=1
you do that, you can get a very high recall.
这么做你可能得到非常高的召回率
That's you end up with a very low value of Vision.
得到非常低的查准率
Conversely,if you have a classifier
相反地 如果你的模型
that predicts y=0 almost all
总是预测y=0
the time, that is, if
就是说
it predicts y one very sparingly.
如果很少预测y=1
This corresponds to setting
对应的
a very high threshold using the notation of previous line.
设置了一个高临界值
And then you can actually
最后 你会得到非常高的
end up with a very high precision with a very low recall.
查准率和非常低的召回率
So the two extremes of either
这两个极端情况
are a very high threshold or a
一个有非常高的临界值
very low threshold, neither of
一个有非常低的临界值
them would give it paticularary good classifier.
它们中的任何一个都不是一个好的模型
And we recognize that is
我们可以通过
by seeing if we end
非常低的查准率
up with a very low
或者非常低的召回率
precision or a very low recall.
判断这不是一个好模型
And if you just take the average of people's ro2.
如果你只是使用(P+R)/2
One does the example the average
算法3的这个值
is actually highest for algorithm 3.
是最高的
Even though you can get
即使你可以通过
that sort of performance by predicting
使用总是预测y=1这样的方法
y1 all the time.
来得到这样的值
And that is just not a very good classifier, right?
但这并不是一个好的模型 对吧
You predict y equals one all
你总是预测y=1
the time is just not a
这不是一个有用的模型
useful classifier if all it does is prints out y equals one.
因为它只输出y=1
And so algorithm one or algorithm
那么算法1和
two would be more
算法2
useful than algorithm three,
比算法3更有用
but in this example algorithm three
但是在这个例子中
has a higher average value of
查准率和召回率的平均值
precision recall than algorithm one and two.
算法3是最高的
So we usually think of
因此我们通常认为
this average of precision recall
查准率和召回率的平均值
as not a particularly good way to evaluate our learning algorithm.
不是评估算法的一个好的方法
In contrast, there is a
相反地
different way of combining precision recall.
有一种结合查准率和召回率的不同方式
It is called the f score and it uses that formula.
叫做F值 公式是这样
So, in this example, here are the f scores.
在这个例子中 F值是这样的
And so we would tell
我们可以通过
from these f scores and
F值来判断
we'll say algorithm 1 has
算法1
the highest f score.
有最高的F值
Algorithm 2 has the second highest and
算法2第二
algorithm 3 has the lowest and so
算法3是最低的
you know, if we go by
因此 通过F值
the f score, we would pick probably algorithm of 1 over the others.
我们会在这几个算法中选择算法1
The f score, which is also
F值
called the f1 score,
也叫做F1值
is usually written f1 score
一般写作F1值
that I have here, but often people will just say f score.
但是人们一般只说F值
It determines use is a
它的定义
little bit like taking the
会考虑一部分
average of precision of recall,
查准率和召回率的平均值
but it gives the lower
但是它
value of precision and recall
会给查准率和召回率中较低的值
- whichever it is - it gives it a higher weight.
更高的权重
And so, you see in
因此
the numerator here that the
你可以看到F值的分子
f score takes a product or position of equal.
是查准率和召回率的乘积
And so, if either position is
因此如果查准率等于0
0 or recall is equal to
或者召回率等于0
0, the f score will
F值也会
be equal to o. So
等于0
in that sense, it kind of combines position and recall.
因此它结合了查准率和召回率
but for the f score to
对于一个较大的F值
be large, both position
查准率
and recall have to be pretty large.
和召回率都必须较大
I should say that there are
我必须说
many different possible formulas for
有较多的公式
combining position and recall.
可以结合查准率和召回率
This f score formula is
F值公式
really, maybe just one out
只是
of a much larger number of
其中一个
possibilities, but historically or
但是出于历史原因
traditionally this is what
和习惯问题
people in machine learning use.
人们在机器学习中使用F值
And the term f score, you
这个术语F值
know, it doesn't really mean
没有什么特别的意义
anything, so don't worry about
所以不要担心
why it's called f score or f1 score.
它到底为什么叫做F值或者F1值
But this usually gives
但是它给了你
you the effect that you want
你需要的有效方法
because if either position is
因为无论是查准率等于0
0 or recall is 0, this
还是召回率等于0
gives you a very low f score.
它都会得到一个很低的F值
And so, to have a
因此
high f score you can't
如果要得到一个很高的F值
need a preserve quality 1
你的算法的查准率和召回率都要接近于1
and completely if p
具体地说
equals zero or i
如果P=0或者
equals zero then this
R=0
gives you the f score equals zero.
你的F值也会等于0
Where as a perfect f
对于一个最完美的F值
score, so if position equals
如果查准率等于1
one and  [xx] equals
同时召回率
one that would give
也等于1
you an f score that's
那你得到的F值
equal to one times one
等于1乘以1
over two times two.
除以2再乘以2
So the f score will be
那么F值
equal to 1 if you
就等于1
have perfect precision and perfect recall.
如果你能得到最完美的查准率和召回率
And intermediate values between 0
在0和1中间的值
and 1, this usually gives a
这经常是
reasonable rank ordering of different classifiers.
回归模型最经常出现的分数
So this video we talked
在这次的视频中
about the notion of trading
我们讲到了如何
off between position and recall
权衡查准率和召回率
and how we can vary the
以及我们如何变动
threshold that we use to
临界值
decide whether to predict y
来决定我们希望预测y=1
equals one or y equals zero.
还是y=0
This threshold that says do
比如我们
we need to be at least
需要一个
seventy percent confident or ninety
70%还是90%置信度的临界值
percent confident or whatever before
或者别的
we predict y equals one and
来预测y=1
by varying the threshold you
通过变动临界值
can control a trade off
你可以控制权衡
between precision and recall.
查准率和召回率
Ross talked about the f score
之后我们讲到了F值
which takes precision and recall
它权衡查准率和召回率
and gives you a single
给了你一个
real number evaluation metric.
评估度量值
And of course, if your goal is
当然 如果你的目标是
to automatically set that
自动选择临界值
threshold, to decide which
来决定
one of y equals 1 or
你希望预测y=1
y equals 0, one pretty
还是y=0
reasonable way to do that
那么一个比较理想的办法是
would also be to try
试一试不同的
a range of different values of thresholds.
临界值
So, try a range of values
试一下
of thresholds and evaluate these
不同的临界值
different threshold on say your
然后评估这些不同的临界值
cross validation set, and then
在交叉检验集上进行测试
to pick whatever value of threshold
然后选择哪一个临界值
gives you the highest f score
能够在交叉检验集上
on your cross validation setting.
得到最高的F值
That would be a pretty reasonable way
这是自动选择临界值的较好办法
to automatically chose the threshold for your classifier as well.
较好办法